Hello everyone, I am Xueli. In this tutorial video, we will learn how to make this set of women's clothing.
If you are a complete beginner user, you can watch our beginner entry video first.
First, let's import a model into the library window.
Double-click to import a T-shirt file into the library window.
We can't directly copy the T-shirt file into the library window, because it is not ready yet.
So we need to arrange the template first.
And here we can see that this template is a bit too big for our Hannah.
So as a reference, let's first change the shape in the second window.
Change the shape to full transparent.
This way, we can refer to the Hanna's body image to fully export the template.
When we export, there is a basis.
We can refer to the shoulder line.
First, we put the template on the line of the front middle and the virtual model.
Then we put the shoulder here.
Then we refer to the line on the side of the waist, extending along the chest to the position near the shoulder point.
After we export, we will align the templates little by little.
And see if they can be aligned.
Now it's still a bit big.
So we'll export it again and align the template.
Now we can see if the shoulder points from the waist to the chest are indeed near,
then we're almost done.
We'll adjust the template slowly after we use this as the basis.
Then we will arrange the template around the virtual model.
Because now there is a line of dust
Press Shift F to open the arrangement point
Click on the board and then click on the blue point
The board will be arranged around the virtual model
Because our board itself is symmetrical
So when we arrange it on the arrangement point
The other side will also be automatically arranged
Finally, the back piece is arranged near the waist
Like our board
After they are arranged
We can press Shift F to hide the arrangement point
You just need to refer to the position in my video
Press the number 2 key to go back to the front view
When rotating the view
We can see that the position of the front and back pieces is relatively low
When they are together
May pass through the body of the virtual model
We try to avoid this kind of problem
So we have to move them
In the process of adjusting the arrangement of the board
Try not to cross-check with the model
Press Ctrl Z to return
Then press the control key
You can turn on the model
Because the default T-shirt in the software
It has the effect of the sewing line itself
In addition, we arranged it well before
Around the virtual model
So after the simulation
This set of T-shirts is directly worn
On the virtual model Hana
Then we will start adjusting the board
First of all, we can first
In the 3D window
Find the line 3D board tool
Click on the clothing
You can draw some straight lines
Double click to complete the creation of this line
Then we turn to the back
Continue to click on the drawing line
In the process of clicking
Press the control key
You can create a curve point
Press ESC
You can cancel the creation
Start drawing again
After drawing
Double click is also completed
Remember to connect to the outside line of the board
Then we use the edit dot tool
Choose all the lines
Press the Shift key
You can choose more
After choosing
In the menu bar in the right-hand corner
Choose the one below the symmetrical column
This board will be based on
The 3D line we just drew on the clothing
To cut
Then we can choose
These extra boards
Delete by pressing the Delete key
Then we press the control key to simulate
Now we can see
The virtual model
There is still some distance between the clothing
After we choose the virtual model
In the attribute editor
You can adjust its surface diameter to 1
After opening the simulation
You will see
The clothing is closer to the virtual model
This is because of the air thickness around the virtual model
It is reduced to 1 mm
When the view is a little farther away
We will find that its shoulders are not in harmony
It looks like there is more
So we use the edit board tool
Find the point where the shoulders lean in
Then move this point
Press the control key
You can drag along its original rhythm
We drag it inward a little
To quickly match the board position
You can click in the 3D window
There will be a blue dot
Then we can find the point to move
After dragging
After opening the simulation
You will see
The shoulder line here is more close
In fact, let's learn
How to do the draw effect
First of all, we press the Shift key
Then select all these lines that form the collar
Then go to the attribute editor
Find the elastic and hook it up
After opening the simulation
The collar will tighten
If this elastic ratio is smaller
It will tighten more
But because our current particle diameter
Is the default 20
Under such a particle diameter
We can't see the wrinkles
So we have to reduce the particle diameter to 10
Then we will see
The wrinkles on the collar will be displayed
The smaller the particle diameter
The more the grid
The more details we can see
Then we can reduce the conflict thickness
If we reduce the conflict thickness
The air thickness around the board will also be reduced
This way, the costume will look more intimate
Then let's take a look
Here in the front chest
There seems to be a small amount of wrinkles
So we have to make it wider in the front and middle
Make it more fabric in front of the chest
So use the edit tool
Select the whole front and middle line
Pull out
Increase this piece of fabric in front of the chest
If our fabric is increased
We have to reduce the elastic ratio
A little bit
Make it tighter
Because wait a minute
The top and the outside
It's going to be a tight women's dress
Then we need to use the shrink rate
To shrink the whole board into a tight state
Then we will see
The shrink rate is divided into the front and the back
Use the edit tool
After selecting the middle board
We will see a arrow
The arrow direction is our front
And it is 90 degrees angled at the end
So now we have to make it tight horizontally
Tighten in horizontal direction
So we have to reduce the end shrink rate a little bit
Here we can gradually
Reduce the end shrink rate from 100 to 70
So the dress becomes a tight dress
Then we can freeze the board